{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
              "A. Jairam Das Daulatram",
              "B. Saiyid Fazal Ali",
              "C. Vishnu Sahay",
              "D. Braj Kumar Nehru"
            ],
            "question": "Who had conferred Gopinath Bordoloi with the title \"Lokapriya\"?",
            "answer": "A. Jairam Das Daulatram"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jorhat",
              "B. Dibrugarh",
              "C. Nagaon",
              "D. Silchar"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the second most populous city in Assam?",
            "answer": "D. Silchar"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Cachar",
              "B. Karimganj",
              "C. Dima Hasao",
              "D. Hailakandi"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is not a administrative districts of Barak Valley in Assam?",
            "answer": "C. Dima Hasao"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jiri River",
              "B. Madhura River",
              "C. Sonai River",
              "D. Jatinga River"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the only left tributary of Barak river?",
            "answer": "C. Sonai River"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1954",
              "B. 1978",
              "C. 1969",
              "D. 1999"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Agricultural University, Jorhat was established in the year ___.",
            "answer": "C. 1969"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Barua Bamungaon",
              "B. Bokajan",
              "C. Chargola",
              "D. Namrup"
            ],
            "question": "The first Sugar Mill in Assam was established in __.",
            "answer": "A. Barua Bamungaon"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bokajan",
              "B. Namrup",
              "C. Jagiroad",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Assam's only chemical fertilizer plant is located in ___.",
            "answer": "B. Namrup"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Mula Gabharu",
              "B. Ambika Kunwori",
              "C. Phuleswari",
              "D. Kuranganayani"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom queen built the Sivadol in Sivasagar?",
            "answer": "B. Ambika Kunwori"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Miles Bronson",
              "B. Nathan Brown",
              "C. Oliver Cutter",
              "D. Alexander Duff"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first American missionary to compile a dictionary of the Assamese language?",
            "answer": "A. Miles Bronson"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bodos",
              "B. Ahoms",
              "C. Rabhas",
              "D. Tiwa"
            ],
            "question": "The 'Me Dam Me Phi' festival is celebrated by __.",
            "answer": "B. Ahoms"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kamrup",
              "B. Nagaon",
              "C. Morigaon",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "In which of the districts, the 'Jonbeel Mela' held every year?",
            "answer": "C. Morigaon"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dima Hasao",
              "B. Cachar",
              "C. Karimganj",
              "D. Karbi Anglong"
            ],
            "question": "Jatinga village is located in which district?",
            "answer": "A. Dima Hasao"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bohag",
              "B. Magh",
              "C. Ahaar",
              "D. Kati"
            ],
            "question": "In which month, Ambubachi Mela is celebrated in Kamakhya Temple?",
            "answer": "C. Ahaar"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. P. Rama Kurup",
              "B. Bishnu Prasad Rabha",
              "C. Bhupen Hazarika",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as 'Kala Guru' of Assam?",
            "answer": "B. Bishnu Prasad Rabha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Parvati Prasad Baruva",
              "B. Pratima Barua Pandey",
              "C. Bhupen Hazarika",
              "D. Phani Sarma"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as 'Geetikavi' of Assam?",
            "answer": "A. Parvati Prasad Baruva"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Homen Borgohain",
              "B. Nirupama Borgohain",
              "C. Mahim Bora",
              "D. Rebati Mohan Dutta Choudhury"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the writer of the novel 'Halodhiya Soraye Baudhan Khai'?",
            "answer": "A. Homen Borgohain"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1992",
              "B. 1993",
              "C. 1990",
              "D. 1973"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Bhupen Hazarika was elected the President of the Asam Sahitya Sabha?",
            "answer": "B. 1993"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Era Bator Sur",
              "B. Shakuntala Sur",
              "C. Chik Mik Bijuli",
              "D. Pratidhwani"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the first film directed by Bhupen Hazarika?",
            "answer": "A. Era Bator Sur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Varman dynasty",
              "B. Pala dynasty",
              "C. Naraka dynasty",
              "D. Koch dynasty"
            ],
            "question": "During which dynasty region, the Madan Kamdev temples in Kamrup was built?",
            "answer": "B. Pala dynasty"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1991",
              "B. 1998",
              "C. 1996",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "From which year, the Assam Divas or the Sukaphaa Divas is celebrated on 2nd December?",
            "answer": "C. 1996"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dhuburi",
              "B. Pancharatna",
              "C. Bongaigaon",
              "D. Jogighopa"
            ],
            "question": "In which location, the Manas River joins the Brahmaputra river?",
            "answer": "D. Jogighopa"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 15th",
              "B. 11th",
              "C. 9th",
              "D. 7th"
            ],
            "question": "Brahmaputra is the _________ longest river in the worlD.",
            "answer": "A. 15th"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 33",
              "B. 21",
              "C. 34",
              "D. 24"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of districts that are on the bank of Brahmaputra river are ___.",
            "answer": "B. 21"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kolkata",
              "B. Guwahati",
              "C. Sibsagar",
              "D. Dibrugarh"
            ],
            "question": "The first Assamese-language magazine Orunodoi was published from __.",
            "answer": "C. Sibsagar"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1975",
              "B. 1957",
              "C. 1964",
              "D. 1947"
            ],
            "question": "The \"Assam Medical College\" was established in the year ___.",
            "answer": "D. 1947"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1894",
              "B. 1893",
              "C. 1896",
              "D. 1892"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, the first Assamese novel Miri Jiyori was published?",
            "answer": "A. 1894"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
              "B. Devakanta Baruah",
              "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
              "D. Chandrakumar Agarwala"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the creator of the imaginary character named 'Kripabor Borua'?",
            "answer": "A. Lakshminath Bezbaroa"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kaliram Medhi",
              "B. Chandradhar Barua",
              "C. Amrit Bhushan Dev Adhikari",
              "D. Rajanikanta Bordoloi"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the second President of Assam Sahitya Sabha?",
            "answer": "B. Chandradhar Barua"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1920 Tezpur",
              "B. 1923 Jorhat",
              "C. 1924 Guwahati",
              "D. 1925 Nagaon"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Lakshminath Bezbaroa presided over the Assam Sahitya Sabha session?",
            "answer": "C. 1924 Guwahati"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1911",
              "B. 1927",
              "C. 1954",
              "D. 1943"
            ],
            "question": "In which year 'O Mur Apunar Desh' was officially adopted as the Assam's state song?",
            "answer": "B. 1927"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Majuli",
              "B. Mangaldoi",
              "C. Sualkuchi",
              "D. Tangla"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the epicenter of the Assam silk industry?",
            "answer": "C. Sualkuchi"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Sankardeva",
              "B. Madhvadeva",
              "C. Chilarai",
              "D. Rudra Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Under whose guidance the Vrindavani vastra was woven by Assamese weavers?",
            "answer": "A. Sankardeva"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Lakshmi Singha",
              "B. Siva Singha",
              "C. Gadadhar Singha",
              "D. Rudra Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Namdang Stone Bridge was constructed during the reign of Ahom king?",
            "answer": "D. Rudra Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kamaleswar Singha",
              "B. Siva Singha",
              "C. Lakshmi Singha",
              "D. Prataap Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Moamoria Rebellion started during the region of ___.",
            "answer": "C. Lakshmi Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Gobar Roja",
              "B. Samaguria Rojaa",
              "C. Parvatia Rojaa",
              "D. Jogeswar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king had the shortest reign of 21 days only?",
            "answer": "B. Samaguria Rojaa"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Siba Singha",
              "B. Rudra Singha",
              "C. Gadadhar Singha",
              "D. Pramatta Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Itakhulir Rann was fought against Mughal during the reign of ___.",
            "answer": "C. Gadadhar Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 14th February",
              "B. 27th March",
              "C. 3rd April",
              "D. 28th April"
            ],
            "question": "The Soti Joymoti Divas is observe on ___.",
            "answer": "B. 27th March"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Guwahati",
              "B. Jorhat",
              "C. Tezpur",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "From which constituency, Bishnu Prasad Rabha was elected as M.L.A in 1969?",
            "answer": "C. Tezpur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bhaity",
              "B. Khoj",
              "C. Aranya",
              "D. Uttaran"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is first Assamese color film?",
            "answer": "A. Bhaity"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Birendra Kumar Bhattacharya",
              "B. Birinchi Kumar Barua",
              "C. Jatindranath Dowara",
              "D. Nalinibala Devi"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the first Assamese recipient of 'Sahitya Akademi Award'?",
            "answer": "C. Jatindranath Dowara"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Iyaruingam",
              "B. Aghari Atmar Kahini",
              "C. Koka Deutar har",
              "D. Pita Putra"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the first Assamese novel to win the 'Sahitya Akademi Award'?",
            "answer": "A. Iyaruingam"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Ambikagiri Raichoudhury",
              "B. Nalinibala Devi",
              "C. Jatindranath Dowara",
              "D. Saurabh Kumar Chaliha"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the writer of the poetry book 'Bon Phul'?",
            "answer": "C. Jatindranath Dowara"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Anand Chandra Barua",
              "B. Homen Borgohain",
              "C. Bhabendra Nath Saikia",
              "D. Mamoni Roysom Goswami"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the writer of the novel 'Mamare Dhara Tarowal Aru Dukhan Upanyasa'?",
            "answer": "D. Mamoni Roysom Goswami"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dharmapala",
              "B. Gopala",
              "C. Jaypala",
              "D. Ratnapala"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the greatest king of the Pala Dynasty of Kamarupa?",
            "answer": "A. Dharmapala"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Murshid Quli Khan",
              "B. Islam Khan",
              "C. Shaista Khan",
              "D. Mir Jumla"
            ],
            "question": "Name the Mughal General who took possession of the Ahom Capital Gahrgaon in 1662?",
            "answer": "D. Mir Jumla"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kandarpeswar Singha",
              "B. Maniram Dewan",
              "C. Piyali Barua",
              "D. Bahadur Gaoburah"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the central figure of the Revolt of 1857 in Assam?",
            "answer": "B. Maniram Dewan"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Rangpur",
              "B. Chittagong",
              "C. Dacca",
              "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "What was the capital of the Province 'Eastern Bengal' and Assam?",
            "answer": "C. Dacca"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1834",
              "B. 1843",
              "C. 1853",
              "D. 1824"
            ],
            "question": "The Treaty of Badarpur was signed between David Scott and Govinda Chandra on March __.",
            "answer": "D. 1824"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1836",
              "B. 1824",
              "C. 1853",
              "D. 1832"
            ],
            "question": "Cachar was placed under the Commissionerate of Dacca in ___.",
            "answer": "A. 1836"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 32",
              "B. 21",
              "C. 40",
              "D. 63"
            ],
            "question": "How many kings do you have during the Ahom Period?",
            "answer": "C. 40"
          }
    ]
}